

AHMET TUFAN HELVACI

Backend Developer



athelvaci@gmail.com



+90 (551) 722 87 97



Istanbul/Turkey

linkedin.com/in/athelvaci



github.com/athelvaci



medium.com/@athelvaci



athelvaci.com

CAREER SUMMARY

Experienced software engineer with 4+ years of remarkable background in Java and Web-Application development. Having extensive industry (e-commerce/finance/insurance) and full life cycle experience in a Java-based environment along with Back-end and Front-end development capabilities. Moreover, experienced in future IT practices for Blockchain and Decentralized Technologies. Believing continuous self-improvement is the key asset for success.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer

11/2020 - Present

DAIMLER MOBILITY

Turkey

- Write JSP and Servlets to add functionality to web application.
- Headless-CMS integration and deployment to Azure cloud.

Technologies used:













Backend Developer

07/2019 - 11/2020

N11.COM

Turkey

- Developed web applications using Java, Spring, Hibernate and SSP.
- Designed and implemented Restful API's for web and mobile applications.
- Integration, bug fix and performance improvements for payment systems.
- Implemented Mobile-Api services for Android, IOS and Mobile-Web clients.
- Involved in fixing the security regarding issues.
- Implemented unit tests and code reviews using Junit and Mockito

Technologies used:















Full Stack Developer

04/2018 - 07/2019

Accenture Turkey

- Gave consultancy services to several projects of an insurance company systems/platforms which aim policy creation and claim operations used by agencies, banks, brokers and 3rd
- Implemented new features (across frontend and backend), maintaining existing code, fixing bugs using Java, Spring, JSF and HTML according to SOLID principles.
- Took responsibility for cost estimation, technical architecture, development, Unit testing and deployment phases.
- Worked closely with business analysts and project stakeholders.

Technologies used:



Web-Services









Maven

Credit Europe Bank

Blockchain Technology R&D (Internship)

Netherlands

2017(3 months)

- Presented my findings on Blockchain technology to different departments of company.
- Designed and implemented smart contracts using Solidity on Ethereum.

Technologies used:





Blockchain Ethereum Solidity Hyperledger

Spring / Hibernate

SKILLS & TOOLS

Web services (Rest-Api / Soap)

Frontend

Backend

Java

Angular

HTML / CSS / JSF

JavaScript

Others

Git Maven Docker Jenkins

Unit Testing Mockito Sourcetree

Blockchain Hyperledger Couchbase Intellij - IDE Jira Agile Waterfall

EDUCATION

- MS in Software Engineering Bogazici University (Turkey) 2020 - 2022
- BSc in Computer Engineering Kadir Has University (Turkey) 2012 - 2017
- Erasmus in Computer Science Coventry University (United Kingdom) 2016 (6 months)
- Erasmus in Computer Science Vilnius Gediminas Technical University (Lithuania) 2014 (6 months)

LANGUAGE

Turkish (Native)

English (Fluent)

INTERESTS

Cycling

Camping

Travelling